Guide to Speeches in the Records of the Office of the President (Dr. John Brademas) RG 3.0.10
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of the President (Brademas), Speeches
1980-1991
RG 3.0.10
New York University Archives
17.0 linear feet (17 boxes)
This collection contains addresses given by John Brademas while serving as President of New York University.
Brademas, John, 1927-
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically.
The files are grouped into one series.
Speeches
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains addresses given by Dr. John Brademas, President of New York University from 1981 to 1991. Most date from the tenure of his presidency, although a few predate it. The speeches are arranged in chronological order from 1965 to 1991.
Biography of John Brademas
John Brademas, now President Emeritus of New York University, served as President from 1981 to 1992. During that time, he led the transition of NYU from a regional commuter school to a national and international residential research university. Before coming to New York, he served as U.S. Representative in Congress from Indiana for 22 years (1959-81), the last four as House Majority Whip. In Congress he earned a reputation for his leadership in education and the arts. Former Chairman of the President's Committee on the Arts and the Humanities, the National Endowment for Democracy and the Board of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York, he is president of the King Juan Carlos I of Spain Center of New York University Foundation. He is a Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and member of the National Academy of Education (USA), The Academy of Athens, European Academy of Science and Arts and National Academy of Education of Argentina. In 2004 he was elected to the New York State Board of Regents by the New York State Legislature.
Access Restrictions
Speeches given before the Board of Trustees of New York University will be restricted for thirty-five years from the date of delivery.
Additionally, this collection is in
off-site storage
.
New York University. Office of the President.; New York University.; speeches.
- Series I
  - Christian Responsibility in the Political Order, December 1965 (Box 611, Folder 1)
    General note
    bar code: 3 1142 042254584
  - Frank Nelson Doubleday Lecture at the Smithsonian Institution (Washington, D.C.), 26 January 1977 (Box 611, Folder 2)
  - Article about Brademas in Art News, September 1980 (Box 611, Folder 3)
  - Commencement address, George Mason University (Fairfax, VA), 10 January 1981 (Box 611, Folder 4)
  - Dinner Honoring Receipt of the Indiana Arts Award by Indiana Arts Commission, 3 February 1981 (Box 611, Folder 5)
  - Breakfast Congress (Washington, D.C.), April 1981 (Box 611, Folder 6)
  - NYU Oxford-Cambridge Boat Race Dinner, Harvard Club (New York, NY), 15 April 1981 (Box 611, Folder 7)
  - Hon. Ray Thorton, President of Arkansas State University (Jonesboro, AR), 16 April 1981 (Box 611, Folder 8)
  - Address on international education, Springfield College (Springfield, MA), 24 May 1981 (Box 611, Folder 9)
  - Convocation, New York University School of Law, 28 May 1981 (Box 611, Folder 10)
  - Interview for NYU Report, 5 June 1981 (Box 611, Folder 11)
  - Testimonial by Mr. Tisch at a dinner for Dr. Brademas, Corcoran Gallery (Washington, D.C.), 8 June 1981 (Box 611, Folder 12)
  - "The Christian Faith and the Public Order," commencement address, McCormick Theological Seminary (Chicago, IL), 9 June 1981 (Box 611, Folder 13)
  - Inauguration invitations, memoranda, and programs, 16 June 1981 (Box 611, Folder 14)
  - Memorandum to deans and the Vice President, 17 June 1981 (Box 611, Folder 15)
  - Welcome Message for Summer Orientation, 1 June 1981 (Box 611, Folder 16)
  - "The Role of the Federal Government in Support of Museums" (Milan, Italy), 24 June 1981 (Box 611, Folder 17)
  - Career in Business Reception, Graduate School of Business Administration, NYU, 9 July 1981 (Box 611, Folder 18)
  - GPA Arts Institute, NYU, 17 July 1981 (Box 611, Folder 19)
  - Address on international education, Foreign Lawyers Workshop Dinner (NYU), 23 July 1981 (Box 611, Folder 20)
  - Anglo-American Conference on University Admininistration, Rockefeller Plaza (New York, NY), 28 July 1981 (Box 611, Folder 21)
  - "The Role of Congress in American Foreign Policy" (Chios, Greece), August 1981 (Box 611, Folder 22)
  - "American Higher Education & The Federal Role", Chios, Greece, August 1981 (Box 611, Folder 24)
  - Speech on arts and museums (Chios, Greece), August 1981 (Box 611, Folder 23)
  - Speech on international education (Chios, Greece), August 1981 (Box 611, Folder 25)
  - "Greek American Involvement in Contempory American Politics" (Chios, Greece), August 1981 (Box 611, Folder 26)
  - Speech at quarterly management committee meeting for ARA Services (NYU), 12 August 1981 (Box 611, Folder 27)
  - Speech, Writers at Work Program (NYU), 18 September 1981 (Box 611, Folder 28)
  - Remarks on freshman orientation (NYU), 21 September 1981 (Box 611, Folder 29)
  - Address honoring George P. Livanos by the American Parkinson Disease Association, undated (Box 611, Folder 30)
  - Speech to present the Presidential Citation to Czeslaw Milosz (NYU), 22 September 1981 (Box 611, Folder 31)
  - "The Architecture of NYU", 23 September 1981 (Box 611, Folder 32)
  - "Architecture of NYU" (delivered by Herbert Silverman), 23 September 1981 (Box 611, Folder 33)
  - Remarks delivered at a luncheon for Cardinal Konig, 28 September 1981 (Box 611, Folder 34)
  - Remarks on the receipt of the Delmore Schwartz Prize by Constance Urdang, 30 September 1981 (Box 611, Folder 35)
  - Crick Lecture & Seminar, 1 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 36)
  - Community Leaders Reception, 5 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 37)
  - Remarks at NYU Alumni Federation Fund Workers Committee Meeting, 6 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 38)
  - Inaugural remarks, 9 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 39)
  - Remarks delivered at City Hall in honor of the proclamation of NYU Week, 13 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 41)
  - The Inaugural Medal of Freedom Award Dinner, 13 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 42)
  - Remarks on Proclamation of NYU Week at City Hall, 13 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 43)
  - Remarks by Herbert Silverman on Proclamation of NYU Week at City Hall, 13 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 44)
  - Remarks by Laurence Tisch on Proclamation of NYU Week at City Hall, 13 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 45)
  - 1981 Commencement, 14 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 46)
  - Press Kit for Dr. Brademas Inauguration, 14 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 47)
  - Dr. Brademas Inauguaral Program, Avery Fischer Hall, (Address on his Inaguration), 14 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 48)
  - Remarks for Inaugural Brunch, Avery Fisher Hall, 14 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 49)
  - Remarks by Laurence Tisch for Toast at Inagural Brunch, 14 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 50)
  - Remarks by Dr. Oliva for Inaugural Ceremonies, 14 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 51)
  - Remarks by Herbert Silverman for Inaugural Ceremonies, 14 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 52)
  - Remarks by Laurence Tisch for Inaugural Ceremonies, 14 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 53)
  - Remarks by Michael Widman (NYU Student Council) for Inaugural Ceremonies, 14 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 54)
  - Remarks at Inaugural Dinner, 14 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 55)
  - Foreword, Sequicentennial Calendar, 1981 (Box 611, Folder 56)
  - Lecture on NYU and the Arts at the Faculty of Arts and Science Dimensions of Change Conference (NYU), 15 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 57)
  - Introduction of Professor James Tobin, 16 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 58)
  - Remarks on federal support for art and museums at the Town Hall Friend of the Arts Award (NYU University Club), 18 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 59)
  - Drafts of the NYU Annual Report, 19 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 60)
  - Remarks on the dedication of the Coles Center, NYU, 24 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 61)
  - Remarks by Laurence Tisch at the Coles Center Dedication (NYU), 24 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 62)
  - Remarks on goals for NYU at the Gallatin Dinner (NYU), 26 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 63)
  - Remarks on an award presented to Dr. Coles at the Varsity Club Dinner (NYU), 27 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 64)
  - Remarks on Dr. Hans-Jochen Vogel's career at a breakfast for Dr. Vogel (Deutsches Haus, NYU), 28 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 65)
  - Remarks at a Degree presentation to Professor Friedrichs (Courant Institute for Mathematical Sciences, NYU), 30 October 1981 (Box 611, Folder 66)
  - Remarks on international studies at the Institute of Fine Arts (NYU), 4 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 69)
  - Remarks on federal funds for education at the Public Education Association Luncheon (Waldorf-Astoria, NY), 4 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 70)
  - Remarks at Dental Alumni Day, 6 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 71)
  - Remarks on government funds for libraries at the New York Library Association Conference, 7 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 72)
  - "The Academy and the Main Human Enterprise," the Miller Conference (Urbana-Champaign, IL), 9 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 73)
  - Liberal Arts Education & Study in Spain, NYU, 13 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 74)
  - Remarks on the liberal arts at the Vanderbilt Associates Dinner (NYU), 18 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 75)
  - Remarks on international education for the U.S. and Greece before the Hellenic Chamber of Commerce, 19 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 76)
  - Remarks on NYU goals before the Association for a Better New York Breakfast (Waldorf-Astoria, NY), 20 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 77)
  - "Higher Learning & the Nation's Future," Carnegie Foundation Colloquium at Georgetown University (Washington, D.C.), 24 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 78)
  - Remarks on fundraising goals before the Division of Student Affairs & Services (NYU), 24 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 79)
  - Remarks on development, 24 November 1981 (Box 611, Folder 80)
  - Remarks on NYU and science before the American Physical Society (NYU), 3 December 1981 (Box 611, Folder 81)
  - Remarks on Draper the astrophysicist at the Henry Draper Symposium (NYU), 4 December 1981 (Box 611, Folder 82)
  - Remarks on problems in higher education before the Higher Education Group (Washington, D.C.), 8 December 1981 (Box 611, Folder 85)
  - Remarks on Congress and foreign policy at the Council on Foreign Affairs Dinner (Washington, D.C.), 9 December 1981 (Box 612, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 042254592
  - Presentation before the University Senate, NYU, 10 December 1981 (Box 612, Folder 2)
  - Remarks on the liberal arts before the Research Libraries Group, NYU, 10 December 1981 (Box 612, Folder 3)
  - Taft Accolades for Walter Mondale, 10 December 1981 (Box 612, Folder 4)
  - Remarks regarding the importance of the School of Continuing Education, NYU, 11 December 1981 (Box 612, Folder 5)
  - Remarks on the importance of the arts and sciences, Faculty of Arts and Science, NYU, 14 December 1981 (Box 612, Folder 6)
  - Remarks on the liberal arts, etc., before the Academic Libraries Frontier (UCLA), 16 December 1981 (Box 612, Folder 7)
  - Remarks at the Institute of Afro-American Affairs Reception, 21 December 1981 (Box 612, Folder 8)
  - Remarks on Presenting a Sesquicentennial Crystal to Bayrd Still, 18 December 1981 (Box 612, Folder 9)
  - Remarks at Faculty Meeting, School of Education, Nursing, Health, and the Arts Professions (SEHNAP), 21 December 1981 (Box 612, Folder 10)
  - Statement for the NYU Annual Report, 1980-1981 (Box 612, Folder 11)
  - Ancillary Services Project Capital Improvements, 1982 (Box 612, Folder 12)
  - Remarks to Faculty, School of the Arts, NYU, 5 January 1982 (Box 612, Folder 13)
  - Remarks on international education before the Fulbright Commission in Israel (Jerusalem, Israel), 12 January 1982 (Box 612, Folder 14)
  - "Night Talk" NYU (NYU Programs in Television), 28 January 1982 (Box 612, Folder 15)
  - Remarks before the Institute of Fine Arts, 3 February 1982 (Box 612, Folder 16)
  - Remarks on the history of NYU and the Village at the Village Chamber of Commerce Lunch (NYU), 3 February 1982 (Box 612, Folder 17)
  - Remarks before the School of Social Work, NYU, 8 February 1982 (Box 612, Folder 18)
  - Remarks to the Faculty of Business Administration, NYU, 9 February 1982 (Box 612, Folder 21)
  - Remarks to the University Senate, NYU, 11 February 1982 (Box 612, Folder 22)
  - Remarks at ribbon cutting, Brittany Residence Hall, NYU, 12 February 1982 (Box 612, Folder 23)
  - Remarks at Deloitte Haskins & Sells Reception, University Club, 18 February 1982 (Box 612, Folder 24)
  - Remarks by Ruth Farkas, Larry Tisch, Herbert Silverman, Dr. Brademas at the Palm Beach Dinner (Palm Beach, FL), 18 February 1982 (Box 612, Folder 25)
  - Report to Dental Faculty (NYU), 1 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 26)
  - Remarks on international education for the United Nations Foreign Language Week (UN Headquarters, NY), 1 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 27)
  - Remarks on the effect of budget cuts on education at the Rockfeller Center Luncheon Club (NY), 2 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 28)
  - Reception & Presentation of Gift from the Education & Vocation for the Deaf Foundation, NYU, 2 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 29)
  - Remarks on the effects of Reagan's budget cuts at a Hearing of the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education (NYU), 5 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 30)
  - Remarks on Reagan-era budget cuts and the arts before the Subcomittee on Post-Secondary Education Hearings (NYU), 5 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 31)
  - Remarks given after being named "Man of the Year" by the Alpha Omega Council (Boston, MA), 6 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 32)
  - Remarks on international education given at the Mason & Sons Dedication Breakfast (NYU), 7 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 33)
  - Remarks on social justice given before an audience involved in social work education, NYU, 7 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 34)
  - Welcome remarks preceding the Chet Huntley Memorial Lecture, NYU, 10 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 35)
  - Remarks regarding outreach in Palm Beach delivered to the University Senate, NYU, 11 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 36)
  - "Does Public Education Have a Future?" given before an audience at the School of Education, Health, Nursing, and the Arts Professions (SEHNAP), NYU, 13 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 37)
  - Remarks on government aid to education, delivered at a luncheon meeting of the NYU Finance Club, Two World Trade Center, 11 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 38)
  - Public Interest Lecture at the Cosmopolitan Club, 15 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 40)
  - Remarks delivered at the Real Estate Institute Annual Urban Leadership Award Dinner, NYU, 18 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 41)
  - Talking points for remarks on the budget delivered before the Faculty Council, NYU, 18 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 42)
  - Talking points for welcome remarks, Congressional Breakfast, NYU, 21 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 43)
  - Welcome remarks delivered before the American Education Research Association, New York, 22 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 44)
  - Remarks on the Reagan budget cuts delivered at the Dental College Sesquicentennial Dinner, 22 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 45)
  - Remarks on the effects of Reagan's budget cuts before a meeting of the faculty of the NYU School of Medicine, 23 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 46)
  - Remarks by Herbert Silverman at the 150th Anniversary of the Dental Center, 23 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 47)
  - Remarks on fundraising at the inauguration of the Dental Center Ambassador Program Inauguration, 24 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 48)
  - Remarks on the study of foreign languages before the Friends of Greek Studies, Ball State University, 24 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 49)
  - Remarks by Dr. Giles Constable, 9th S. J. Brademas, Sr., Lecture, Ball State University (Muncie, IN), 25 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 50)
  - Moskowitz Lecture, NYU, 31 March 1982 (Box 612, Folder 51)
  - Remarks on the Reagan administration before the Publishers Lunch Club (Yale Club), 1 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 52)
  - Remarks on the effect of budget cuts on education delivered before the Administrators' Roundtable, CUNY, 2 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 53)
  - Remarks on housing and development delivered at the Law School Faculty Meeting, NYU, 5 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 54)
  - Remarks at a reception for the Journal of International Law & Politics, 6 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 55)
  - Remarks at Lord Caradon Dinner, NYU, 12 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 56)
  - Remarks at Lord Briggs Lecture, NYU, 14 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 57)
  - Remarks on development and housing delivered at a University Senate Meeting, NYU, 15 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 58)
  - Remarks on the effects of budgets cuts by the Reagan administration, delivered at the Postgrad & University Hospital Alumni Association Dinner, 20 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 59)
  - Remarks at the Leo Jaffe Dinner, NYU, 21 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 60)
  - Welcome remarks, David Kriser Seminar (Topic: Nuclear Arms), NYU, 22 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 61)
  - Founders Day Dinner & Convocation, NYU, 22 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 62)
  - Remarks on a citation honoring Theodore M. Hesburg at Founders Day, 22 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 63)
  - Commencement address, 160th Commencement Exercises at the University of Pittsburgh, 25 April 1982 (Box 613, Folder 64)
  - Remarks on the effects of Reagan-era budget cuts delivered at the School of Social Work Benefit, NYU Club, 25 April 1982 (Box 613, Folder 65)
  - "Effect of Public Policy on Human Development," talking points, Sunrise Semester, 26 April 1982 (Box 612, Folder 66)
  - Remarks delivered at the installation of Howard Squadron as President of the American Jewish Congress (with Ambassador Ghorbal of Egypt), 28 April 1982 (Box 613, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 042254600
  - Remarks on business and education technology delivered before the Association for a Better NY & American Jewish Community, 28 April 1982 (Box 613, Folder 2)
  - Remarks by Drs. Brademas and Oliva at the Italian Heritage & Culture Week Proclamation Ceremony, Washington Square Park, 30 April 1982 (Box 613, Folder 3)
  - Remarks on the history of experimental education delivered on the occasion of the tenth anniversary of the Gallatin Division, NYU, 30 April 1982 (Box 613, Folder 4)
  - Introductory remarks for a dinner honoring Auchincloss, 19 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 5)
  - Welcome remarks delivered at the Conference on Central America & The Caribbean, NYU, 2 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 6)
  - Talking points on financial aid for a meeting with Student Senators Council, NYU, 6 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 7)
  - Remarks on Washington/Albany delivered before the University Senate, NYU, 6 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 8)
  - Remarks on the Village delivered at the Caring Community Lunch, NYU, 6 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 9)
  - Talking points for commencement address, Indiana University (South Bend, IN), 11 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 11)
  - Commencement address for the University of Southern California, 13 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 12)
  - Talking points regarding the School of Business and Public Administration for a meeting with the Marketing Society, 18 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 13)
  - Gallatin Fellows Dinner, 19 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 14)
  - Auchincloss Dinner at Rockefeller University, 19 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 15)
  - Remarks on the Lewis Levine Language Laboratory delivered at the Japan International Christian Univeristy Foundation Luncheon, NYU, 20 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 16)
  - Talking points on the differences between Indiana and Washington, D.C., delivered before the Washington Square Association, 20 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 17)
  - Talking points on the Lewis Levine Language Laboratory delivered before the Faculty Council, NYU, 20 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 18)
  - Commencement address at Manchester College (North Manchester, IN), 23 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 19)
  - Introductory remarks at the Andrew Huxley Convocation & Dinner, NYU Medical Center, 24 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 20)
  - Remarks on Governor Carey on his receipt of the Weiler Award, 25 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 21)
  - Alumni Federation Dinner, NYU, 27 May 1982 (Box 613, Folder 22)
  - Mayor Koch, NYU Medical School Commencement, Lincoln Center, 2 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 23)
  - NYU Address to the 34th Annual Business Conference, Rutgers University, 3 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 24)
  - Remarks on financial aid delivered before the Administrative Management Council, NYU, 9 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 26)
  - Remarks by Laurence Tisch at the Trustees Pre-Commencement Dinner, NYU, 9 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 27)
  - 150th NYU Commencement, Washington Square Park, 10 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 28)
  - Remarks by Mr. Tisch, NYU Commencement, 10 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 29)
  - Script for NYU Commencement, 10 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 30)
  - Remarks by H.R. Silverman, NYU Commencement, 10 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 31)
  - Remarks by Laurence A. Tisch, NYU Commencement, 10 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 32)
  - Commencement address, Kalamazoo College (Kalamazoo, MI), 12 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 33)
  - Remarks on international education before the Citizens Budget Commission Press, NYU, 14 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 34)
  - Remarks on the attributes necessary to being a lawyer, delivered before the National Association of College & University Attorneys, 8 July 1982 (Box 613, Folder 35)
  - Remarks introducing the recipients of honorary degrees at the Trustees Pre-Commencement Dinner, NYU, 9 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 36)
  - Commencement address, DePaul University (Chicago, IL), 13 June 1982 (Box 613, Folder 37)
  - Remarks on U.S. trade with Japan at a luncheon meeting at the International House of Japan (Tokyo, Japan), undated (Box 613, Folder 38)
  - Seminar on U.S.-Japan Economic Relations (Aspen, CO), 16 August 1982 (Box 613, Folder 39)
  - Remarks on the Education Commission of the States (James Bryant Conant Award), (Portland, OR), 20 August 1982 (Box 613, Folder 40)
  - ICA International Comparative Literature Congress, 23 August 1982 (Box 613, Folder 41)
  - Remarks at the Academic Convocation for New Students, NYU, 9 September 1982 (Box 613, Folder 42)
  - Remarks at the Education Panel of the Biennial Conference of the National Italian American Foundation (Washington, D.C.), 10 September 1982 (Box 613, Folder 43)
  - Opening Convocation, University of Richmond (Richmond, VA) and remarks delivered at the Biennial Conference of the National American Foundation (Portland, OR), 15 September 1982 (Box 614, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 042254618
  - Talking points for meeting with students, NYU, 25 September 1982 (Box 614, Folder 3)
  - Lecture by Douglas Yates, "The Search for Democracy & Efficiency in American Government" (Cambridge, MA), 27 September 1982 (Box 614, Folder 4)
  - Remarks before the Executive Committee of the Faculty Council, NYU, 30 September 1982 (Box 614, Folder 5)
  - Remarks at a luncheon in honor of Jorge Luis Borges, New York Institute for the Humanities, NYU, 1 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 6)
  - Remarks delivered at the St. Francis of Assisi 8th Centenary Celebration, NYU, 5 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 7)
  - Remarks delivered at the Annual Dinner of the American Association of Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, 5 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 8)
  - Remarks delivered at the Graduate School of Business AdministrationTel Aviv Reception (Tel Aviv University, Israel), 7 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 9)
  - Remarks at the Gallatin Association Dinner, 7 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 10)
  - Interview on "Public Hearing," broadcast on WCBS, 8 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 11)